A Guide to the Records of the Executive Mansion of Governor Robert F. McDonnell, 2010-2014
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Records of the Executive Mansion of Governor Robert F. McDonnell, 2010-2014
The Library of Virginia
50966, 51169
2.45 cu. ft. (6 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (2010-2014: McDonnell)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of Governor Robert F. McDonnell on 29 July 2013 (Accession 50966).
Transferred from the Office of Governor Robert F. McDonnell on 29 January 2014 (Accession 51169).
Biographical Information
Robert F. McDonnell was elected 71st governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia in November 2009 and inaugurated on 16 January 2010. He served until 11 January 2014.
Scope and Content
Records, 2010-2014, of the Executive Mansion during the administration of Governor Robert F. McDonnell. The collection is housed in 6 boxes and arranged into two series, Series I: General; and Series II: First House: two centuries with Virginia's first families, by Mary Miley Theobald. The records include articles, book drafts, correspondence, invitations, photographs, and other sundry materials. The Director of the Executive Mansion during Governor McDonnell's administration was Sarah Scarbrough.
Series I: General includes articles, meeting minutes and notes from the Citizens Advisory Council on Furnishing and Interpreting the Executive Mansion, documentation of repairs done to the mansion, thank you's sent, and various photographs of past and present Governors and their families. Also included is information on events such as a BBQ Cook Off and Easter Egg Hunt, held at the mansion.
Series II: First House: two centuries with Virginia's first families, includes information on the publication of the book on the history of the Virginia Executive Mansion by Mary Miley Theobald. This series includes draft copies of the book, copies of photographs and art work used in the book, articles about the publication, correspondence regarding fees and sales of the book, and tickets for the premiere unveiling of the book.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: General, 2010-2014
Series II: First House: two centuries with Virginia's first families, 2010-2014
Contents List
- Series I: General, 2010-2014, Extent: .90 cu. ft. (2 1/2 boxes). (Box 1-3)
  - Articles, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles (see also oversize articles), 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - BBQ Cook Off, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Citizens Advisory Council on Furnishing and Interpreting the Executive Mansion, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Civil War Sesquicentennial, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Stories for Mansion book, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Thank Yous, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Thank Yous, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Thank Yous, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Documentation of plaster repairs to the dining room ceiling of the Mansion, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fireplace, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Floors, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gleaning Day, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Governor's Easter Egg Hunt, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Inside Stately Living," 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, Reply cards for Reunion Honoring Virginia's Former Governors, First Ladies, their Families, and Descendants, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Invitations, Misc., 2011 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Mansion archives, Governors and families, ca. 1922-2012 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Photographs, Mansion archives, Governor portraits (copies), 1776-2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Mansion archives, Governor portraits (copies), Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, Mansion archives, Misc., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Mansion archives, Misc., ca. 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Misc., ca. 2012 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Capitol Foundation, 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Year of the Virginia Historic Home," 2013 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series II: First House: two centuries with Virginia's first families, 2010-2014, Extent: 1.55 cu. ft. (3 1/2 boxes). (Box 3-6)
  - Artwork, 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Background and publication, 2009-2012 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Companion dvd, Blue Ridge PBS, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Draft, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fees, Book, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Misc., 2013 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Assorted Christmas, ca. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Before and After Renovation of Mansion, ca. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Photographs, Interiors, Assorted, ca. 1990-2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Renovation, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Garden Week, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Gov. Trinkle and family, ca. 1920-1930 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, Gov. Allen, Christmas at Mansion, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, View from Bank of America, ca. 1970-1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Misc., 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, Mansion, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sales, Book, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sponsorships (No), 2012 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sponsorships (Yes), 2012 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tickets, Red carpet premiere, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Transparencies, Assorted, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 200th Anniversary Video, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Articles (oversize), 2012-2013 (Box 5)
  - Draft copy of book with notes, 2012-2013 (Box 5)
  - Draft copy of book, 2012-2013 (Box 6)